Guide to the Robert Grenier Papers
Department of Special Collections
- Series XII. RG Published Works 1967 - 1998, Signed copies of RG publications (e.g. SENTENCES, Burns' Night Heard, Oakland, etc.) needed to complete RG Archive collection - 1 box.
  - B. Dusk Road Games, Poems 1960 - 1966 (Pym-Randall Press, 1967), RG's first book of poems (RG ts. in VIII.A. above) (Box 029)
    - 1. Clothbound copy no. 105 (of 350 printed), w/ dust jacket (photo of old car vanishing down wooded lane found by Emily Lord on trash night in Newtonville, MA), w/ photos inserted of RG & wife, Emily Lord Grenier, [ca. 1965] (72 pp. total) (Box 029)
    - 2. Paperback copy, (unnumbered, one of 650 printed) w/ photo of old car on front & back covers (72 pp. total) (Box 029)
  - C. Selected Poems: Georg Trakl, ed. Christopher Middleton, pub. as Cape Edition 23 by Jonathan Cape/Grossman Publishers (London, 1968), Paperback copy (unnumbered) w/ wrappers containing translations from Trakl's German poems by Michael Hamburger, David Luke, CM & (9 by) RG (RG tss. of these & other Trakl trans. in VI.A.8. above & see RG paper on Traki in VI.B.1. above) (125 pp. total) (Box 029)
  - D. Sentences Toward Birds, 41 poems centered on 4" by 6" index cards (most of which were later collected in RG's SENTENCES), (unnumbered) (43 pp. total) (Box 029)
  - E. Series, Poems 1967 - 1971, pub. by Barrett Watten's This Press in San Francisco in 1978, Paperback (unnumbered, one of 600 printed) w/ covers by Francie Shaw (cf. RG ts. in VIII.K. above) (144 pp. total) (Box 029)
  - F. SENTENCES, pub. by Michael Waltuch's Whale Cloth Press in Cambridge, MA in 1978, 500 poems centered on 5" by 8" index cards in blue folding Chinese cloth box (poems written 1971 - 1978 ), no. 173 (of 200 made) (see history in IX.A. above) (503 pp. total) (Box 029)
  - G1. CAMBRIDGE M'ASS ['black' trade edition], pub. by Lyn Hejinian's Tuumba Press in Berkeley in 1979, 265 poems on 40" by 48" poster poems written ( 1977 - 1979 ), (typed/designed/laid out by RG) (unnumbered) (RG tss. In VII.M. & N. above) (40" by 48" poster in tube) (Box 029)
  - G2. CAMBRIDGE M'ASS ['grey' trial version], pub. by Lyn Hejinian's Tuumba Press in Berkeley in 1979, 265 poems on 40" by 48" poster poems written 1977 - 1979 )., (typed/designed/laid out by RG) (unnumbered) (RG tss. in VII.M. & N. above) (40" by 48" poster in tube). Being a lighter 'grey' trial version (abandoned in favor of darker 'black' trade edition in section XII.G) (RARE / SAVE!) (Box 034)
  - H. Oakland, pub. by Lyn Hejinian's Tuumba Press in Berkeley in 1980 May, 92 poems arranged on 5½" by 8½" pages (poems written 1979 - 1980 ), (designed by RG/printed by LH), no. 143 (of 450 made) (see RG tss./'dummy' in VIII.R. above) (38 pp. total) (Box 029)
  - I. Burns' Night Heard, chapbook pub. as Tansy 15 by John Moritz's Tansy Press in Lawrence, KS in 1982 Apr, A poem w/ 7 parts (unnumbered) (10 pp. total) (Box 029)
  - J. A Day At The Beach, pub. by James Sherry's Roof Books in New York City in 1985, 216 poems arranged (3 per page) on 6" by 10" pages in 3 sections (of 24 pp. each) (poems written 1980 - 1982 ) (says ' 1984 ' on copyright page but issued in early 1985 ) (designed/typed by RG/produced by Diane Ward) w/ photos of RG at beach on inside covers by Donald Guravich (unnumbered) (see history in IX.B. above) (88 pp. total) (Box 029)
  - K. Forgotten, pub. as 'Poetcard' by Alastair Johnston at Poltroon Press in Berkeley in 1985, RG poem (1 p. total) (unnumbered) (Box 029)
  - L. Through The Manacle, pub. as 43.5 by 59 cm. broadside designed & printed by Frances Butler at Poltroon Press in Berkeley in 1985, RG poem, w/ letterpress & pochoir illustration by Frances Butler, in oak/glass frame (unnumbered, one of 50 made) (see description/photo in III.A.23. above) (Box 036)
  - M. Attention / Seven Narratives, pub. as Fascicle 28 in A Curriculum Of The Soul series, ed. John Clarke, for The Institute Of Further Studies by Albert Glover's Glover Publishing in Canton, NY in 1985, RG essay (unnumbered) w/ cover by Guy Berard (RG ms. Drafts in VIII.S. above) (38 pp. total) (Box 029)
  - N. Phantom Anthems, pub. by Leslie Scalapino's 0 Books (& RG) in Oakland in 1986, 118 poems variously arranged on 7½" by 9" pages in 9 sections (poems written 1982-86) (designed/typed & produced by RG) w/ covers by LS (unnumbered, one of 1000 made) (see history in IX.C. above) (112 pp. total) (Box 029)
  - O. What I Believe Transpiration/Transpiring Minnesota, pub. by Leslie Scalapino's 0 Books (& RG) in Oakland in 1991, 86 poems darkly xeroxed from RG ts./holograph drawing writings on 8½" by 11" acid-free pages in sturdy black hinged box (poems written 1987 - 1989 ) (designed/typed & produced by RG) w/ an introduction on inside box covers by LS (unnumbered, one of 400 made) (see history in IX.D. above) (68 pp. total) (Box 029)
  - P. 12 from r h y m m s, pub. by David Baratier's Pavement Saw Press in Scotia, NY in 1996, 12 poems from RG color holograph drawing project r h y m m s ( 1989 ) reproduced in blue/black/red & green on 8½" by 11" acid-free pages in envelope (designed by RG/produced by DB from RG color xerox images) (unnumbered, one of 110 made) (14 pp. total) (Box 029)
  - Q. OWL / ON / BOU / GH, pub. by Simone Fattal's Post-Apollo Press (& RG) in Sausalito, CA in 1997, 32 4-color xerox images made from RG holograph drawing poems on 11" by 17" acid-free paper in black portfolio (designed/produced by RG) (numbered as indicated, one of 100 made) (see history in IX.E. above) (34 pp. total) (Box 035)
  - R. RG Online Works, As of 2002 May, online versions of three RG color holograph drawing poem sequences can be found at Karl Young's Light and Dust Mobile Anthology of Poetry. Although, alas, no 'signed copy' of digital texts can be included here, Karl Young has agreed to 'reverse engineer' disk copies of RG works pub. at his site, so that material records (ca. 10 disks) can document these publications & (w/ appropriate equipment) be used in future to access/view the following sequences directly in the library. (Box 029)
    - 1. 10 Pages from r h y m m s, trans. by KY from RG color xerox images of holograph drawing poems (10 pp. total) (Box 029)
    - 2. For Larry Eigner, w/ intro by KY, trans. by KY from 45 RG color xerox images of holograph drawing poems (46 pp.) (Box 029)
    - 3. Greeting & Pond I, w/ intro by KY, trans. by KY from Ken Botto color slides (in XI .F. 1. above), of RG Drawing poems (50 pp. total) (see black/white printout in VIII.Y. above) (Box 029)
- Series XIII. RG Teaching Materials 1968-1992, (1 box total)
  Principally course descriptions, reading lists, RG notes, assignments, materials discussed in class, tapes of classes, student work, catalogues & curriculum development papers from literature & writing courses at UC Berkeley, Tufts University, Franconia College, New College of California & Sonoma State University, organized chronologically & counted (by pages of text ("pp.") ).
  - A. University of California at Berkeley 1968 - 1970 (Box 031)
    - 1. Department of English Faculty & Staff Directory 1968-1969
      (2 pp. total)
    - 2. Materials from RG sections of English 1A, First Year Reading & Composition, Spring Quarter 1969, Fall Quarter 1969
      (36 pp. total)
    - 3. Materials from RG sections of English 1B, First Year Reading & Composition, Winter Quarter 1969, Spring Quarter 1969
      (15 pp. total)
    - 4. Materials from RG's English 108, Readings in Contemporary American Poetry, Winter Quarter 1970
      (68 pp. total)
    - 5. Materials from RG's English 143B & English 141, Advanced Poetry Writing, Winter Quarter 1969 & Fall Quarter 1969
      (71 pp. total)
  - B. Tufts University 1970 - 1971 (Box 031)
    - 1. Materials from RG's English 175-C, 20th Century Poetry, Fall Term 1970
      (31 pp. total)
  - C. Franconia College 1971 - 1976 (Box 031)
    - 1. RG's lists of recommended books in the field of literature for Franconia College Library & Bookstore, 1971
      (18 pp. total)
    - 2. Some RG course descriptions, Fall 1971 - Fall 1975
      (12 pp. total)
    - 3. Materials from RG's Modern American Poetry, Fall Term 1971
      (30 pp. total)
    - 4. Reading list for RG's Tales of (Humor) Mystery & Terror, Fall Term 1971
    - 5. Reading lists & materials from RG's Contemporary American Poetry, Spring Term 1972 & Spring Term 1973
      (14 pp. total)
    - 6. Reading lists from RG's The Cantos of Ezra Pound & Problems in Modern Poetry, Fall Term 1972
      (3 pp. total)
    - 7. Reading list for The Work of William Carlos Williams, as taught by RG & student-teacher George Franklin, Fall Term 1972, and by RG, Spring Term 1975
      (1 p. total)
    - 8. Materials from RG's The Work of Louis Zukofsky, Fall Term 1973
      (21 pp. total)
    - 9. Materials from RG's Gertrude Stein Workshop, Spring Term 1974
      (41 pp. total)
    - 10. Materials from RG's Melopoeia, Spring Term 1974
    - 11. Materials from RG's The Dictionary As Literature, Fall Term 1974
      (11 pp. total)
    - 12. Reading list & materials from RG's Kerouac, Burroughs & Ginsberg, Fall Term 1975
      (8 pp. total)
    - 13. Materials from RG's Theories Of The Poem / Poems And Their Origins, Fall Term 1975
      (45 pp. total)
    - 14. Franconia College curriculum planning materials, by RG & others, 1971-1974
      (35 pp. total)
    - 15. Franconia College annual catalogues: 1970-1976
  - D. New College of California 1979 - 1982 (Box 031)
    - 1. Materials from RG's Prosody classes, Fall Term 1980 & Fall Term 1981
      Largely consisting of RG's anthology of lyric poetry in English from anonymous 15th Century verse to Leslie Scalapino, being exemplary instances of verse structure with RG holograph analyses (293 pp. total)
    - 2. Audiotape record of RG's Prosody class, Fall Term 1980 (September 1, 1980 - December 17, 1980)
      Complete except for one class (October 29, 1980), consisting of 20 archival-quality 90 minute cassette tapes.
    - 3. Reading list & materials from RG's Poetics of the Personal Voice, Spring Term 1982
      (38 pp. total)
    - 4. Folder containing catalogue materials & announcements re New College Program in Poetics, 1980 - 1984
      (c. 3/4" thick)
  - E. Sonoma State University Spring Term 1986 (Box 031)
    - 1. English Department course descriptions, faculty profiles and schedule of classes, Spring 1986
      (27 pp. total)
    - 2. Exemplary texts presented & discussed in RG's English 418-1, Advanced Poetry Writing
      (107 pp. total)
    - 3. Student writing discussed & read aloud in RG's English 418-1, Advanced Poetry Writing
      (95 pp. total)
  - F. The Naropa Institute 1992 Summer Program (Box 031)
    - 1. Catalogue & business materials re RG's participation in Naropa Summer Program
      Includes course description for RG's workshop, Spiritual Topographies & notice of lecture, Drawing Form Nature (see materials referenced in sections V.A.24. and 26., and V.C.14. & 15). (64 pp. total)
  - G. RG's Curriculum Vitae 1998, (2 pp. total) (Box 031)
- Series XIV. Reel-to-Reel Audiotapes of Poets Reading Their Works 1958 - 1974
  From RG's tape collection (1/3 box total)
  - A. Robert Creeley Tapes
    - 1. RC reading in ca. 1958 poems later collected in For Love & a story, "The Grace" in The Gold Diggers (Box 032)
      (tape given RG by Marthe Rexroth in Spring 1962 in San Francisco)
    - 2. RC reading poems from For Love at UC Berkeley, October 18, 1962 (side 1) & at UC Berkeley at the Berkeley Poetry Conference, 1965 July 22 (sides 1 & 2) (Box 032)
    - 3. RC reading from For Love, Words, Pieces & A Day Book at Mills College, February 24, 1970 (side 1) & at California College of Arts & Crafts, February 26, 1970 (side 2) (Box 032)
    - 4. RC reading from For Love, Words, Pieces & A Day Book at UC Berkeley, 1970 Feb 25 (Box 032)
      (intro RG)
  - B. Robert Grenier Tape
    - 1. RG reading very early, apprentice (unpublished) poems into Wollensak tape recorder in Cambridge, MA ca. 1962-1963 (Box 032)
  - C. Kenneth Irby Tape
    - 1. KI reading early poems into Wollensak tape recorder in Cambridge, MA 1962 Dec - 1963 Feb (Box 032)
  - D. Paul Blackburn Tape
    - 1. House tape made by Paul Blackburn & given to Kenneth Irby (who copied this tape for RG) (Box 032)
      With a sampling from PB's collection: early Edward Dorn poems read by ED, Octavio Paz reading with English translations of Paz read by Clayton Eshelman (side 1), Louis Zukofsky reading (from "A-9" & "A-11") & PB reading his poems (side 2) (this tape dates from ca. 1962-63)
  - E. Larry Eigner Tape
    - 1. Tape recorded by RG at 23 Bates Road, Swampscott, MA of LE talking with RG & LE's brother & sister-in-law, Mr. & Mrs. Joseph Eigner on 1971 June 14 (Box 032)
      (both sides)
  - F. Clark Coolidge / Richard Grossinger Tape
    - 1. CC reading poems from Space at Franconia College, 1971 Oct 9 (Box 032)
      (side 1)
    - 2. RG reading his poems at Franconia College, 1971 November 4 (Box 032)
      (side 2)
  - G. James Tate Tape
    - 1. JT reading his poems at Franconia College, 1971 Dec 2 (Box 032)
  - H. Alice Notley Tape
    - 1. AN reading her poems at Franconia College in ca. 1972 (Box 032)
  - I. Louis Zukofsky Tape
    - 1. LZ reading from "A-23" at Franconia College, 1974 May 9 (Box 032)